What’s your name, honey?
你叫什么名字？亲爱的
Uh, I’m Joe
嗯，我是乔伊
I teach middle school band
我教中学乐队
Connie, got to go for it
康妮，加油！
I play this jazz teacher who’s sort of stuck
我扮演一个爵士乐老师
配 "乔伊"
Uh, happily stuck, but still stuck in a job where he’s teaching jazz
呃，快乐地陷入，依旧沉沦在教爵士乐
which is a sort of a throwback of trade
有点复古的东西
and when it comes to musical trade, he’s teaching jazz to his
而且当谈及音乐职业时，他在教他的
to his little, you know, his little kids in school
小，你知道，他的小家伙们
But Joe has always dreamed of being something else
但是乔伊总是梦想着干点别的
联合导演/剧本
In his heart, he’s a musician at heart
在他心里，他是一个音乐家
and since he was very young Joe always wanted to be
并且在他非常小的时候，乔伊总是想成为
a professional jazz musician
一个专业的爵士乐音乐家
You could say that jazz music is the dream that Joe’s been pursuing
你可以说爵士乐就是乔伊一直追求的梦想
on nights and weekends, his entire adult life
在晚上，在周末，在他人生全部成年时间
This is big gig that’s coming up
有一个现场演奏会即将到来
and he wants to go play for it
并且他想去上台表演
He finally goes and auditions and he get lost
他最后去参加了试演并且沉浸在自己的表演中
and for musicians or anybody out there when you get lost in your craft
对于音乐家或者其他任何人来说，当你迷失在你的演奏中
He’s just in his thing auditioning no nerves he went
他只是做好他自己而已，试演中没有任何的紧张
and they said wow you’re great
他们说，哇你演奏得真棒
you will have the gig
你将会拥有现场演奏的机会的
And then has an accident that causes his soul to leave his body
但在那之后一场事故让他的灵魂脱离了他的身体
配 "22"
and almost go to the Great Beyond
他的灵魂差点去了“生之彼岸”
And so, he is trying to get back into his body and back to his life
于是，他在努力尝试回到他的身体回到他的生活
Is this heaven? - No.
这儿是天堂吗？ - 不是
Is it H.E. Double Hockey sticks?
那这是H.E.两个曲棍球球棍吗？(即HELL地狱)
hell…
地狱…
It’s easy to get turned around
这二者确实很容易搞反
This isn’t the Great Beyond, it’s the Great Before
这不是亡灵的世界，而是还未出生灵魂的世界
The Great Before?
还未出生的灵魂的世界？
I played a character named 22
我扮演一个名叫22的角色
who is a soul that’s never been born
她的灵魂从未诞生过
because even though the people in the Great Before
因为即使所有在未诞生灵魂的世界的人
have been trying to convince her
一直在尝试去说服她
She had a lot of mentors trying to convince her that life is great
她有很多导师试图让她相信生活是美好的
and she should go live on earth
她应该去地球上生活
She is very suspect of it
她对此非常怀疑
she thinks it sounds scary, painful, difficult, depressing, smelly
她觉得听起来吓人，痛苦，困难，压抑，难闻
She just doesn’t want any part of it
她只是不想变为其中之一
She is a Joe’s chance
她是乔伊的机会
if he can kind of convince her to go back
如果他能说服她回去
then maybe he’ll get a chance to go back also
那么他也许也会有机会回去
Initially I think that character’s name was 107,337,217,322
起初我认为那个角色的名字是107337217322
导演
we called her 22 for short
我们简称她为22
But in the end we decided it’s actually funnier if she is just 22
但是在最后我们决定如果她只有22岁的话会更有趣
That’s how long she’s been up there
这是她存在的时间
and she still wants nothing to do with earth
并且她仍旧不想和地球扯上关系
You know, we thought of her a little bit, 22 is kind of like a teenager
你知道的，我们想象她很小，22就有点像一个
who thinks they know everything
总以为他们无所不知的青少年
In 22’s case, she can make a pretty compelling argument that she does
在22的例子中，她可以提出一个非常有说服力的论点
because she’s been looking down on earth and taking notes
因为她一直在俯视地球做笔记
for a long, long, long time
很长很长很长一段时间
and to her it looks like a lot of suffering and disappointment
对她来说，这看起来像是很多痛苦和失望
and why, why get mixed up in that
所以为什么，为什么要卷入其中
22 is a, I would say lack of a better word, not cynical
22是一个，我缺少一个更好的词来形容她，不是愤世嫉俗
but it’s like doesn’t really see the reason
但好像不知道原因
She’s been there, quite literally, thousands of years and refuses to go to earth
她已经在那里，确切地说，几千年来，拒绝去地球
She cannot get a ticket; she cannot get her earth badge to change
她拿不到票，她拿不到她的地球通行证去换
Because she thinks that there’s nothing good about going to earth
因为她觉得去地球没什么好处
So, we have the situation where we have a soul
所以我们有了这样一个局面
who doesn’t want to die
一个不想死的灵魂
being stuck with a soul who doesn’t want to live
被困在一个不想活下去的灵魂里
22 has been at the You Seminar for quite some time
22在人生研讨班已经有一段时间了
and has had such notable mentors as Gandhi, Abraham Lincoln, and Mother Teresa
曾有甘地、亚伯拉罕·林肯和特蕾莎修女等著名导师
I made her cry
我把她弄哭了
Ignore that
忽略这个
you got the talented Tina Fey
你知道蒂娜·菲是非常有天分的
who’s just, you know I mean, come on
你知道，我是说
That her mind and the way she works is amazing
她的思想和工作方式令人惊叹
Plus, she’s a writer as well you know she started out as a writer
另外，她是个作家你知道她一开始就是个作家
and you know being on Saturday night live so just to be able to
并且你知道在周六晚上直播
sort of go back and forth
就是为了能来回走动
even when we weren’t in the same room with each other
即使当我们不在同一个房间
He was only in the same room a couple of times
他只是在同一个房间里呆过几次
But just being in her presence man made everything you know, elevated
但就在她面前，让你知道的一切东西都高尚起来了
Yeah, I read her biography and she said she spent a lot of her youth
是的，我看过她的传记，她说她花了很多青春
standing on the sidelines with the “cool kids”, making fun of people
和“酷孩子”站在一起，取笑别人
And I think in a way that really personifies 22
我认为在一定程度上这就是22的人格化
She’s, she doesn’t want to get involved with all these messiness and drama
她，她不想卷入这些混乱和戏剧
She wants to be on the side, just judging
她只想站在一边，去评判
Jamie Foxx plays Joe Gardner
杰米·福克斯扮演乔伊·加德纳
and he’s incredible in the movie
他在电影里真是太棒了
because one, he’s a really great actor
因为第一，他是个很棒的演员
but also because he is a musician himself
但也因为他自己是个音乐家
All the parts of Joe’s character that are tied to his love of music
乔伊角色中所有与他对音乐的热爱有关的部分
just feel really authentic
感觉很真实
and connected coming from Jamie
是和杰米那里紧密联系着的
and he’s just super expressive with his voice
他的声音很有表现力
Guy can do everything; you know he’s great dramatic actor
这家伙什么都能做，你知道他是个伟大的喜剧演员
he’s got comedy chops, he loves music, he understands music
他有喜剧天赋，他热爱音乐，他懂音乐
He’s a great musician himself and he has this unrelenting optimism and energy
他本人就是一位伟大的音乐家，他有不屈不挠的乐观精神和活力
that I think all of which were essential for really bringing Joe to the screen
我认为所有这些都是把乔伊搬上银幕的必要条件
It’s almost as if there was a computer program
就好像有一个电脑程序
where you wanted to feed all these traits into the program
你想把这些特质都输入到这个程序中
and ask for like, OK,
问它，好，现在帮我筛选
feed all the traits for the prefect person to play Joe Gardner
最完美的拥有所有特质来扮演乔伊·加德纳的人
It would spit out Jamie Foxx
它会说杰米福克斯
This is the guy I was telling you about
这就是我跟你说起的人
my old middle school band teacher, Mr. Gardener
我以前的中学乐队老师，加德纳老师
Call me Joe, Dorothea
叫我乔伊，桃乐丝
I mean Mrs. Williams, it’s a pleasure, wow this is amazing
我是说威廉夫人，这是我的荣幸，哇这太棒了
Oh, Joe is, Oh gosh
哦，乔伊是，哦天哪
He is so enamored of Dorothea
他是如此地崇拜桃乐丝
配 "桃乐丝"
he recognizes what a great musician she is
他意识到她是一个多么伟大的音乐家
He recognizes the opportunity that’s before him
他意识到机会就摆在他面前
He knows he better not to mess up that this may be a one-time thing
他知道他最好不要搞砸，这可能是一次性的事情
that this was a gift that literally landed in his lap
这是一份真正落在他腿上的礼物
that sort of was orchestrated from years previous
这是几年前精心策划的
because he, Joe, was actually the mentor
因为他，乔伊，是真正的导师
the middle school teacher of this drummer
这位鼓手的中学老师
One of the students who’s a drummer
其中一个鼓手学生
who, because of his artistry and wound up it Dorothea’s band
因为他的艺术技巧和桃乐丝的乐队产生了矛盾
and this particular day, someone falls out
在某一天，有人闹翻了
and it’s time for the understudy to go on
现在就是替补该上场的时候了
What I enjoyed about what Jamie Foxx
我喜欢的是杰米·福克斯
配 "阿寇"
brought to the role of Joe Garden was that
带给角色乔伊·加德纳的
there’s a space that musicians often get in that
音乐人总会在里面找到一个空间
mere mortals don’t tend to understand
凡人不会明白
and that’s when you get into a zone
就是当你进入一个区域的时候
people tend to tag it as like, musician’s face
人们往往给它贴上一个“音乐家的脸”的标志
You know, whenever your eyes are closed
你知道，当你闭上眼睛
and you’re making these wired faces
你就会描绘出脸的线条
that’s sort of a spiritual experience
那是一种灵魂体验
You know, that’s where you get into the zone
你知道，那就是你进入这个区域的地方
and I love the fact that Jamie’s character often gets to
我喜欢的就是杰米的角色经常去
go to that place and explain to people why us musicians
那个地方并且向人们解释为什么我们是音乐家
go to that place, where, you know,
去那个地方，你知道
we make these wired faces, and our eyes are closed
我们做出那些奇怪的表情，在我们眼睛闭上的时候
We’re going to a place another dimension unknown
我们即将去往一个未知的地方
Only known to other creatives and that’s the zone
只有其他具有创造力的人才知道的，就是那个地方
Uh, sorry I zoned out a little back there
呃，对不起，我有些走神了
Joe Gardener, where have you been?
乔伊·加德纳，你去哪了？
I’ve been, uh, teaching middle school band
我一直，呃，教中学乐队
But on the weekends, I…
但是在周末，我…
You got a suit? Get a suit, teacher
你有西装吗？穿上西装
A good suit, back here tonight
一套好的西装，今晚回来
First shows at nine, sound checks at seven
九点开始演出，将在七点试音
We’ll see how you do
我们将会看你怎么样
The first writer I work with was Mike Jones
与我共事的第一位作家是迈克·琼斯
Mike and I crafted the world and the basic bones of the story
迈克和我精心设计了这个世界和故事的基本框架
But as we run into the specificity of Joe
但是当我们遇到乔伊的特别之处
and wanting to know more about this character
想更多地了解这个角色
We realized, though, we need somebody who has more to bring
不过我们意识到我们需要一个能带来更多东西的人
from this background and Kemp,
从这个背景，此外，坎普
not only a great writer, but he ended up
不仅是一个好的作家，而且
stepping in so many different ways
有很多不同的方法演绎
in regard to set design what kind of posters
关于布景设计什么样的海报
will be at Joe’s house or mom’s house
会在乔伊家以及他妈妈家
and Queens, you know, the authenticity of the neighborhood
以及纽约皇后区的街景，你知道的，社区的真实性
Of course, Joe and his passions
当然，乔伊和他的激情
and what kind of music he listens to and all this
他听什么样的音乐和所有这些
we ended up making Kemp co-director
所以我们最后让坎普成为了联合导演
because he just, was bringing so much to almost
因为他给我带来了很多，几乎是每一个部门
every department and I think it really ups the whole film
我认为这对整个电影来讲非常有利
It’s the incredible Pixar, you know I mean
这是不可思议的，皮克斯，你知道我的意思
the way they think 4 or 5,6 dimension you know
他们的思维方式是四维，五维，六维的
that’s I mean you think about it the movies that have come before
我是说你想想以前的电影
when I deal with these types of subject matters are really
当我处理这些类别的题材的时候很重要的是
really opened up different sides of your head
去打开了你思维的不同的侧面
What the movie is telling us and actually what Joe learns
电影告诉我们的就是乔伊真正学到的
is that there is more to living life than achievement
是生活的意义不仅仅是为了达成成就
which is a really interesting thing to try to take in
这是一件非常有趣的事情
You know, there’s just being present and being in the world
你知道，只是存在于当下，存在于这个世界
and making connections and having feelings
建立联系和感情
there’s more to life than checking boxes of things
生活中有更多的东西，而不仅仅是检查盒子里
you’ve wanted to achieve
你想去实现的东西
Jamie you know Jamie is just too quick with it
杰米，你知道，杰米太快了
and he’s so fast on his feet
他步调非常快
so he has brought a lot of character, a lot of warmth to Joe
所以他能给乔伊带来很多性格，很多温暖
and in the course of the story, this, you know
在故事过程中，这个，你知道的
different characters take over different bodies and
不同的角色掌管不同的身体
but you just enjoy following Jamie in all his machinations
但是你仅仅只需跟随杰米在他所有的小花招
in whatever way he shows up
不管他以什么方式出现
We can’t taste it either?
我们也尝不到吗？
All that stuff is in your body
所有的这些感官都在你的肉体内
No smell, no taste, or touch
没有嗅觉，味觉，或者知觉
See?
发现了吗？
OK, I got it
好的，我懂了
心灵奇旅